Cell: (646) 580-2891 Email: zeshannali84@gmail.com

System Engineer

A seasoned Cloud and DevOps Engineer/Administrator with strong automation skills. Experience with automation and orchestration tools while working with a software development team and utilizing best practices for integration and maintenance of a software and hardware baselines.

Technology Summary

Server OS:

Automation/Build Tools

Programing

Programing

Python and Shell Script

Subversion and Git

Professional Experience:

Bank of America, New York, NY Feb 2020 – Present System / Cloud Engineer

- Providing infrastructure-as-code utilizing terraform and AWS Cloud Formation
- Design, manage, and maintain additional tools to automate operational processes.
- Used Terraform and Ansible, migrate legacy and monolithic systems to Amazon Web Services
- Used Terraform scripts to configure AWS resources
- Wrote Ansible playbooks from scratch in YAML. Installing, setting up & Troubleshooting Ansible, created and automated platform environment setup
- Define and deploy monitoring, metrics, and logging systems Analyze all aspects of existing application infrastructure and recommend modifications that will enhance application reliability, availability and scalability
- Designed and delivered mission-critical infrastructure to maintain consistent availability and performance
- Work on jira assignment for proper documentation
- Grasped user needs and drove development to working prototype stages
- Working with DevSecOps team to develop and refine CI/CD pipeline from tickets to deliverables
- Set up Git repositories and SSH Keys in Bitbucket for Agile teams
- Helped teams to configure Webhooks in Bitbucket to trigger automated builds in Jenkins
- Setting up Jenkins master, adding the necessary plugins and adding more slaves to support scalability and agility
- Automated infrastructure provisioning on AWS using Terraform and Ansible

HSBC, Jersey City, NJ Mar 2019 – Feb 2020 System Engineer

- Implementing IaC and IaaS using Terraform, Ansible and Docker on RHEL7
- Building, maintaining, and executing automated CI / CD pipelines for DEV, QA, and PROD environments
- Attempting to use new build tools, and dashboards such as Github Actions
- Visualize and understand real-time system health, usage, and performance metrics
- with CloudWatch
- Help maintain the infrastructure and service health monitoring process using Splunk
- and CloudWatch
- Apply appropriate controls to pipelines to facilitate fast release cycles with minimal
- risk in Prod
- implementing continuous integration with (Jenkins), release management, and
- validation (Github)
- Identify opportunities to automate and deliver self service capabilities for the most
- common infrastructure and tasks
- Participate in sprint planning (Jira)

M&T Bank, New York, NY Jun 2017 – Mar 2019

Linux System Administrator

- Monitored system performance of virtual memory, disk and CPU utilization.
- Work with a team to install and configure Nagios to monitor IT infrastructure.
- Package management using RPM, yum and dnf in Redhat Linux.
- Support my team to create a system build (kickstart).
- Worked on Managing the Cloud Environment using Terraform & Ansible.
- Managed and optimize the Continuous Delivery tools like Jenkins.
- Development team used a Git branching strategy that included develop branches, feature branches, staging branches and master. Pull requests and code reviews were performed.
- Support a 24/7 production environment and perform the day-to-day management, maintenance, optimization, backup, and ongoing reporting requirements.
- Own the creation of builds and coordinate the creation of source-code tags and branches with development groups

Education:

Kingsborough College Bachelor's Degree in Computer System (expected June 2023)